What's this "important matter" you wanted to talk about?
&lrm;Chuyện quan trọng em muốn nói là gì?
Just get in.
&lrm;- Vào xe đi. &lrm;- Ừ, được rồi.
Hey, wait a minute. This seems awfully familiar.
&lrm;Khoan đã, cảnh này hình như quen quá.
As I recall, when I opened the door that time...
&lrm;Mình nhớ lần trước lúc mình mở cửa ra...
I got you! I got you good!
&lrm;Mắc lừa rồi nhé! Anh mắc lừa rồi!
She thought it was the most hilarious thing ever.
&lrm;Cô ấy nghĩ đó là trò vui nhất trên đời.
Okay, I'll fall for it again today, hook, line and sinker.
&lrm;Được thôi, &lrm;lần này mình sẽ tiếp tục mắc lừa vậy.
Come on, give the pranks a rest!
&lrm;Thôi nào, dẹp trò ấy đi.
What are you doing?
&lrm;Anh đang làm cái gì thế?
I said this was important, didn't I?
&lrm;Em đã nói là chuyện quan trọng mà.
That's what you said last time, and then you pulled a prank on me.
&lrm;Thì lần trước em cũng nói y như thế &lrm;mà lại bày trò hù dọa anh.
- Listen... - Yes?
&lrm;- Nghe này... &lrm;- Sao cơ?
Can't you tell what it is?
&lrm;Anh không đoán ra à?
Can't I tell what what is?
&lrm;Anh không đoán ra gì ư?
All I can tell is that you're as lovely as ever–
&lrm;Anh chỉ muốn nói rằng em đáng yêu như...
Quit being an idiot!
&lrm;Anh đừng ngốc thế!
Come on, just tell me what it is!
&lrm;Thôi nào, nói anh nghe là chuyện gì đi.
I'm missing my you-know-what.
&lrm;Em mất rồi.
Missed?! You don't mean–
&lrm;Mất ư? Ý em là?
It's embarrassing, so don't tell anyone, got it?
&lrm;Chuyện này xấu hổ lắm &lrm;nên anh đừng nói với ai đấy.
O-Of course not!
&lrm;Đương nhiên rồi.
What am I going to do? Someone's going to have to take responsibility.
&lrm;Em phải làm sao đây?
I-I'll do right by you.
&lrm;Anh sẽ chịu trách nhiệm với em.
Takagi...
&lrm;Takagi...
Hang on... In cases of marriage between police officers,
&lrm;Khoan đã. Nếu như hai cảnh sát lấy nhau,
to say nothing of two officers in the same precinct,
&lrm;chưa nói đến việc hai cảnh sát &lrm;công tác ở cùng khu vực,
given the possibility of issues arising from a married couple working together,
&lrm;chỉ nói đến chuyện của một đôi &lrm;làm việc chung với nhau,
one of them is supposed to transfer out.
&lrm;thì một người sẽ phải chuyển công tác.
Satou is the belle of Division 1, so if I cause her to transfer out...
&lrm;Satou là hoa khôi sở cảnh sát, &lrm;nếu mình khiến cô ấy chuyển công tác
there's no telling what hell the senior detectives will put me through.
&lrm;thì không biết các cấp trên &lrm;sẽ đì mình thế nào.
So I'll have to transfer to some other precinct.
&lrm;Có thể chính mình &lrm;sẽ chuyển sang khu vực khác.
No, I could resign and be a stay-at-home dad.
&lrm;Không, mình có thể xin nghỉ &lrm;để làm ông bố nội trợ.
Understood!
&lrm;Vâng, hiểu rồi.
We're on our way.
&lrm;Chúng tôi sẽ đến ngay.
We got a tip that a suspect we're after was spotted in Beika Town.
&lrm;Em vừa nhận được tin &lrm;nghi phạm đang ở khu Beika.
We're going to check it out.
&lrm;- Chúng ta phải đi kiểm tra. &lrm;- Ừ.
-M-Miwako is having a baby? -What happy news!
&lrm;- Miwako có thai rồi à? &lrm;- Đúng là tin vui!
A chic and dashing detective show that holds up under the blazing sun!
&lrm;Một câu chuyện tình cảnh sát &lrm;dưới ánh mặt trời.
Will Satou finally profess her feelings to Takagi?
&lrm;Liệu Satou có thổ lộ với Takagi?
A perfect alibi! A mystery written in the language of flowers!
&lrm;Chứng cứ ngoại phạm hoàn hảo. &lrm;Ẩn ngữ của hoa.
Always determining the one truth with the body of a child and the mind of an adult,
&lrm;Kiên định với chân lí, &lrm;cơ thể trẻ con nhưng trí tuệ người lớn,
his name is Detective Conan!
&lrm;tên cậu là Thám tử Conan!
Come on, all three of you are yawning?
&lrm;Thôi đi, sao cả ba cậu đều ngáp thế?
What are you, Haibara?
&lrm;Haibara có ngáp đâu.
Well, excuse me for yawning a lot.
&lrm;Tớ biết rồi. Do chơi game chứ gì.
We can't help it!
&lrm;Bọn tớ không ngừng được.
Titan Hunter just came out, and it's too much fun!
&lrm;Trò &lrm;Titan Hunter&lrm; mới ra vui lắm!
We all got sucked into it.
&lrm;Bọn tớ đều bị cuốn vào.
Sheesh, you're wasting your precious summer vacation playing some game?
&lrm;Các cậu lãng phí kì nghỉ hè quý giá &lrm;để chơi game à?
Oh, right! I got my daddy to help me and I made it to rank 5!
&lrm;À, bố giúp tớ lên đến cấp năm rồi cơ đấy.
- Seriously? - I keep getting eaten by the blue titan!
&lrm;Thật ư?
What kind of game is this?
&lrm;Là game gì thế?
From what I hear, it's a roleplaying game
&lrm;Theo những gì nghe được, &lrm;tớ đoán đấy là game nhập vai.
where you protect your castle from a race of attacking titans.
&lrm;Cậu phải bảo vệ lâu đài &lrm;khỏi cuộc tấn công của mấy con quái vật.
Now that you mention it, the strategy guide goes on sale today, doesn't it?
&lrm;Hình như hôm nay họ phát hành &lrm;sách hướng dẫn chiến thuật đúng không?
Wow, right!
&lrm;Ừ, đúng rồi.
Hey, do you think they have it in that mini-mart over there?
&lrm;Này, cậu có nghĩ ở cửa hàng tiện lợi kia &lrm;có bán sách ấy không?
Let's go see!
&lrm;- Bọn mình đi xem thử đi! &lrm;- Ừ, đi thôi.
I thought we were going to go play soccer in the park!
&lrm;Tớ tưởng bọn mình &lrm;định ra công viên chơi bóng mà.
I guess not.
&lrm;- Hết cách rồi. &lrm;- Chán thật!
Was there an accident there?
&lrm;Đằng kia đã từng có tai nạn à?
And those flowers...
&lrm;Những bông hoa đó...
I think those are called false dragonheads.
&lrm;Hình như nó được gọi là giả long đầu,
They signify...
&lrm;tượng trưng cho...
Edogawa.
&lrm;Này, Edogawa.
What are you doing? Keep up.
&lrm;Cậu đứng đấy làm gì? Đi thôi.
Oh. Sure.
&lrm;Ừ.
That sure was a surprise.
&lrm;Thật kì lạ!
I can't believe a total stranger looked so much like our suspect.
&lrm;Ai mà ngờ có người giống &lrm;nghi phạm của chúng ta đến thế.
That's for sure.
&lrm;Phải đấy.
It's a little late, but do you want to grab lunch somewhere around here?
&lrm;Cũng muộn rồi, anh có muốn ăn trưa &lrm;ở đâu đó gần đây không?
Oh, sure!
&lrm;Ừ, được.
How about pickles and ice cream or something?
&lrm;Dưa muối và kem hay gì đó không?
Huh? Why would I want that?
&lrm;Gì cơ? Tại sao?
Whoa, awesome!
&lrm;Ôi, tuyệt quá!
- This says it's called the Haouken! - It's so cool!
&lrm;- Nó gọi là Haouken. &lrm;- Hay quá!
It says its ATK stat is over 10,000, and is the only blade feared by the titans!
&lrm;Chỉ số tấn công lên đến hơn 10.000
It's B&amp;W, so you can't tell what it really looks like, though.
&lrm;Nhưng mà ảnh này màu đen trắng, &lrm;không biết nó trông như thế nào.
It says here that you can only get it if you're rank 8
&lrm;Ở đây nói là cậu chỉ lấy được nó &lrm;khi lên cấp tám
and defeat a big-ass, red titan!
&lrm;và đánh bại tên trùm quái vật màu đỏ.
I won't be getting it anytime soon...
&lrm;Chắc còn lâu tớ mới lấy được nó.
Oh, I have that sword.
&lrm;Này, tớ có rồi đấy.
Its hilt is shiny and gold, and the design on the blade is red!
&lrm;Cán có màu vàng, &lrm;còn hoa văn trên lưỡi gươm màu đỏ.
Noriya Makabe (7) 1st-year Grade School Student
&lrm;NORIYA MAKABE (7) &lrm;LỚP MỘT
It seems like you still need to get a bunch of buff items
&lrm;Có lẽ cậu vẫn còn phải qua nhiều chặng
to level up the sword afterwards, though.
&lrm;mới lên đến cấp lấy được thanh gươm ấy.
Oh, wow! You made rank 8, then?
&lrm;Hay quá! Cậu lên đến cấp tám rồi ư?
Yep!
&lrm;Ừ.
Hang on, aren't you in the class next to ours?
&lrm;Khoan đã, cậu ở lớp bên cạnh đúng không?
You aren't lying to make yourself sound cool, are you?
&lrm;Cậu không nói dối để tự tâng bốc đấy chứ?
I'm not lying!
&lrm;Tớ không có nói dối.
Right, big brother Toshinari?
&lrm;- Đúng không, anh Toshinari? &lrm;- Đúng thế.
You worked hard for it.
&lrm;Em đã làm rất tốt.
Huh? That's the guy from the street...
&lrm;Ồ, đó là anh chàng lúc nãy ở ngoài đường.
If you really got the Haouken, I'd sure love to see it!
&lrm;Thế cậu cho bọn mình xem nó được không?
-Me, too!
&lrm;- Tớ cũng muốn xem. &lrm;- Cả tớ nữa.
Want to come over to Toshinari's place, then?
&lrm;Thế qua nhà anh Toshinari đi.
It's okay, isn't it?
&lrm;Được không anh?
Toshinari Shiga (25) Graduate Student
&lrm;TOSHINARI SHIGA (25) &lrm;SINH VIÊN CAO HỌC
Wait for me in the car, then. I'll go pay our bill.
&lrm;Các em ra đợi anh ngoài xe nhé. &lrm;Anh đi trả tiền đã.
That comes to 1,350 yen.
&lrm;Tổng cộng là 1.350 yên.
Put it on my card, please.
&lrm;Tôi trả bằng thẻ.
- Of course. Number of payments? - One-time charge.
&lrm;- Vâng. Số lần trả là bao nhiêu ạ? &lrm;- Một lần.
Of course.
&lrm;Vâng.
He drives an import and has a platinum card...
&lrm;Anh ấy lái xe nhập và có thẻ bạch kim...
Maybe he's a trust fund kid.
&lrm;Xem ra anh ta giàu có đấy.
This place is a dump!
&lrm;- Nơi này chán thế! &lrm;- Im đi, Genta!
It may not look like much, but home is where you make it.
&lrm;Trông thế thôi nhưng vẫn là nhà anh ở mà.
I'll park the car, so you go on inside.
&lrm;Anh đi đậu xe, các em vào đi.
Okay!
&lrm;Vâng. &lrm;PHÒNG SỐ BA &lrm;SHIGA
- It's so pretty... - Awesome!
&lrm;- Đẹp quá đi mất! &lrm;- Tuyệt vời!
Sheesh...
&lrm;Trời ạ!
It's full of junk food, instant noodles and mini-mart bento boxes.
&lrm;Toàn là đồ ăn nhanh,
Their diet is on display here.
&lrm;Nhìn là biết ăn uống kiểu gì rồi.
- Hey, Haibara. - What?
&lrm;- Này, Haibara. &lrm;- Gì đấy?
Did you smell something?
&lrm;- Cậu có ngửi thấy mùi gì không? &lrm;- Không hề.
I don't think there's any kitchen garbage in here.
&lrm;Tớ không nghĩ có rác nhà bếp &lrm;trong này đâu.
No, in the hall before we came in.
&lrm;Không, ở trong sảnh &lrm;trước lúc bọn mình bước vào ấy.
No, I didn't notice anything.
&lrm;- Không, tớ không để ý. &lrm;- Thế à.
Hey, where do you get off poking around someone's home?
&lrm;Này, sao cậu lục lọi nhà người ta thế?
Tell me something, Noriya...
&lrm;Này, Noriya.
Did your brother just move here?
&lrm;Anh cậu vừa dọn đến đây à?
No, it was about a month ago.
&lrm;Không, khoảng một tháng trước rồi.
Before summer vacation, he lived in the same condo building as my folks.
&lrm;Trước khi nghỉ hè, &lrm;anh ấy ở cùng khu nhà với bố mẹ tớ.
And Toshinari isn't my brother. He's my cousin.
&lrm;Anh Toshinari không phải anh ruột của tớ &lrm;mà là anh họ.
He's the son of my mom's older sister.
&lrm;Anh ấy là con trai của bác gái tớ.
My dad is on an overseas business trip right now,
&lrm;Bố tớ đang đi công tác nước ngoài,
and Mom has left for a week to take care of him,
&lrm;mẹ tớ cũng đi một tuần để lo cho bố,
so I'm staying here with Toshinari while she's away.
&lrm;nên tớ ở đây với anh Toshinari &lrm;trong lúc mẹ vắng nhà.
You're staying here for a week?
&lrm;Cậu ở đây một tuần à?
Yeah. Plus, Mom asked me to do something for her.
&lrm;Ừ. Mẹ nhờ tớ giúp.
Toshinari's big sister died in a traffic accident six months ago.
&lrm;Chị của anh Toshinari đã mất &lrm;vì tai nạn giao thông sáu tháng trước.
He's been really sad ever since,
&lrm;Anh ấy rất buồn từ dạo ấy,
so Mom asked me to stay with him and cheer him up.
&lrm;nên mẹ bảo tớ ở đây &lrm;để giúp anh ấy vui lên.
Then he was laying those flowers at the spot where she died...
&lrm;Thế nên anh ấy mới đặt hoa &lrm;ở chỗ chị ấy mất.
Oh, right! I got him to show me some pictures of her earlier!
&lrm;Đúng rồi! Tớ có bảo anh ấy &lrm;cho tớ xem hình chị trước đây.
She was really nice. She used to take me camping all the time.
&lrm;Chị ấy rất dễ thương và hay đưa tớ &lrm;đi chơi cắm trại.
Can I see?
&lrm;- Tớ xem được không? &lrm;- Được.
That's strange. She isn't looking into the camera in any of these last ones.
&lrm;Lạ thật.
And what are these? There are little holes in the tops of the pictures.
&lrm;Mà đây là gì nhỉ?
Th-That was Toshinari!
&lrm;Giọng anh Toshinari.
The hallway... Don't tell me--
&lrm;Ngoài sảnh. Chẳng lẽ...
It was coming from apartment #4?
&lrm;Phòng số bốn.
I knew it, that smell was...
&lrm;Mình biết ngay mà, cái mùi lúc nãy...
Conan?
&lrm;Conan?
What is it?
&lrm;- Chuyện gì thế? &lrm;- Các cậu lùi lại đi!
Haibara, call the police. Tell them someone has died here.
&lrm;Haibara, gọi cảnh sát.
On it.
&lrm;Hiểu rồi.
What's that?
&lrm;Đấy là cái gì?
The pictures pinned up on this cork board...
&lrm;Những bức ảnh treo trên bảng...
The pictures and the sun-bleached areas don't quite line up.
&lrm;Ảnh và phần ngoài rìa không khớp nhau.
And it's not just one or two of them.
&lrm;Không phải chỉ có một hai tấm bị.
What could cause that?
&lrm;Tại sao thế nhỉ?
She isn't looking into the camera...
&lrm;Chị ấy không nhìn thẳng vào camera.
There are little holes in the tops of the pictures...
&lrm;Có những cái lỗ trên đầu tấm ảnh.
I don't believe it.
&lrm;Có lẽ nào...
The culprit who did this is...
&lrm;Hung thủ làm việc này là...
It can't be...
&lrm;Không lẽ nào...
I have to say,
&lrm;Phải nói là
I had no idea things had progressed so far with those two.
&lrm;tớ không ngờ chuyện giữa hai người ấy &lrm;diễn ra nhanh đến thế.
They're gonna get hitched for sure now.
&lrm;Chắc là họ sẽ quyết sớm thôi.
Things are gonna get dangerous for Takagi, though.
&lrm;Nhưng có vẻ không hay ho lắm với Takagi.
Hm? Dangerous how?
&lrm;Hả? Là sao?
Imagine what'll happen when the detectives find out.
&lrm;Thì cậu cứ tưởng tượng &lrm;nếu những người khác biết chuyện xem.
Oh, you have a point.
&lrm;Ừ, đúng rồi. &lrm;Satou có nhiều người hâm mộ lắm.
- He's in trouble. Seriously. - He sure is.
&lrm;- Anh ấy gặp rắc rối rồi. &lrm;- Đúng rồi.
In serious trouble.
&lrm;Rắc rối to đấy.
Your mouth is saying one thing, but your face is saying another.
&lrm;Miệng nói thế nhưng trông cậu &lrm;không có ý đấy thì phải.
The victim is Hiroto Yasutomi. Age 31, job hopper.
&lrm;Nạn nhân là Hiroto Yasutomi,
Forensics puts estimated time of death
&lrm;Theo pháp y, thời điểm tử vong là
sometime between 7:00 and 9:00 last night.
&lrm;trong khoảng từ bảy đến chín giờ tối qua.
Repeated stabbings to the chest and abdomen, huh?
&lrm;Bị đâm vào ngực và bụng à?
Then you were the first person to find the body?
&lrm;Anh là người đầu tiên &lrm;phát hiện xác nạn nhân ư?
You're Toshinari Shiga, the next-door neighbor?
&lrm;Anh là Toshinari Shiga, &lrm;hàng xóm của nạn nhân phải không?
Yes.
&lrm;Vâng. Trước đó tôi đậu xe trong bãi.
and when I was going to my own apartment,
&lrm;Rồi khi đi lên phòng mình,
I noticed a strange smell coming from this one.
&lrm;tôi thấy có mùi lạ từ phòng này.
The door was unlocked, so I let myself in. That's when I found him like this.
&lrm;Cửa không khóa nên tôi bước vào
I shouted in surprise, and that's when this boy,
&lrm;Tôi la lên và rồi cậu nhóc
a friend of my cousin Noriya's, barged in.
&lrm;bạn của em họ tôi, Noriya, xông vào.
Conan?
&lrm;Conan à?
Then the girl who reported the body was...
&lrm;Thế cô bé báo án là...
Me.
&lrm;Là cháu ạ.
We all came over to hang out at Noriya's cousin's place today.
&lrm;Hôm nay bọn cháu &lrm;đến nhà anh họ của Noriya chơi.
I have to say, you're every bit the angel of death that Mr. Mouri is.
&lrm;Cháu có vẻ giống thiên thần báo tử &lrm;hệt như bác Mori nhỉ?
I keep finding you at murder scenes.
&lrm;Chỗ nào có người chết là cô lại thấy cháu.
G-Gosh, you two sure arrived at the scene quickly.
&lrm;Hai cô chú đến hiện trường nhanh thật.
We got a tip that an employee at a nearby florist's looked like a wanted suspect.
&lrm;Cô chú nhận được tin là &lrm;có nhân viên ở tiệm hoa gần đây
It turned out to be a false alarm, though.
&lrm;Nhưng hóa ra chỉ là hoang báo.
We happened to be in the neighborhood, so we caught the case.
&lrm;Cô chú tình cờ đang ở gần đây &lrm;nên nhận vụ này.
If Takagi hadn't been whispering with that employee about flowers,
&lrm;Nếu chú Takagi không huyên thuyên &lrm;với người đó về hoa cỏ,
we could have gone straight back.
&lrm;thì cô chú đã về được rồi.
We were still in the area because we were eating lunch!
&lrm;Chúng ta ở khu này &lrm;vì đang dùng bữa trưa đấy chứ.
You were talking about flowers?
&lrm;Huyên thuyên về hoa cỏ ư?
Are you gonna give some to somebody?
&lrm;Chú định tặng hoa cho ai à?
If it was to Det. Satou, he wouldn't have been whispering about it!
&lrm;Nếu tặng cho cô Satou &lrm;thì chú ấy đâu có huyên thuyên như thế.
He must be cheating. You think so, too?
&lrm;Chú ấy nói dối đấy.
I-I am not!
&lrm;Đâu... có.
To get back on track...
&lrm;Quay lại vụ án...
If he died between 7:00 and 9:00 last night,
&lrm;Nếu nạn nhân chết &lrm;khoảng từ bảy đến chín giờ đêm qua,
why don't you ask Noriya and Toshinari about it?
&lrm;sao chúng ta không hỏi thử &lrm;Noriya và anh Toshinari?
They were next door, so they might have heard strange sounds or something.
&lrm;Họ ở bên cạnh nên có thể đã nghe thấy &lrm;tiếng động lạ hay gì đấy. &lrm;Lúc ấy, cháu đang xem ti-vi &lrm;với anh Toshinari.
The Kamen Yaiba movie was on.
&lrm;Ti-vi đang chiếu phim &lrm;Kamen Yaiba&lrm;.
I watched that, too!
&lrm;Tớ cũng có xem nữa.
Me, too! Wasn't it awesome?!
&lrm;Tớ cũng vậy. Phim hay quá nhỉ.
It was on from 7:00 to 9:00 for its first TV broadcast!
&lrm;Đúng là phim đó chiếu từ bảy đến chín giờ &lrm;và phát sóng lần đầu.
You didn't hear any strange sounds or moaning while it was on?
&lrm;Cháu không nghe thấy tiếng động lạ &lrm;hoặc tiếng rên rỉ khi đang xem phim à?
Yeah! During the movie, our neighbor banged on the door
&lrm;Vâng. Trong lúc cháu xem phim, &lrm;hàng xóm của cháu cứ đập ầm ầm vào cửa
and yelled at us to turn it down.
&lrm;bắt bọn cháu vặn nhỏ lại.
Around what time was that?
&lrm;Lúc ấy là mấy giờ?
I think it must have been around 7:30.
&lrm;Tôi nghĩ là khoảng 7h30.
I apologized through the door and turned down the volume.
&lrm;Tôi xin lỗi qua cánh cửa rồi vặn nhỏ lại.
Which means that Mr. Yasutomi was still alive at that time.
&lrm;Nghĩa là lúc ấy ông Yasutomi vẫn còn sống.
Did you hear anything strange after that?
&lrm;Sau đó anh có nghe gì lạ nữa không?
Well... Kamen Yaiba is one of those superhero shows,
&lrm;À, &lrm;Kamen Yaiba&lrm; là &lrm;thể loại phim siêu anh hùng
so there was a lot of screaming and explosions.
&lrm;cho nên có rất nhiều tiếng la hét &lrm;và tiếng nổ.
Even if there had been any strange noises, I might not have noticed.
&lrm;Dù có tiếng lạ chắc tôi cũng không chú ý.
Besides, his body was found by his kitchen sink,
&lrm;Hơn nữa, xác ông ấy nằm cạnh bồn rửa bát,
which is two rooms away from where we were watching TV.
&lrm;rất xa chỗ chúng tôi ngồi xem ti-vi.
Come to think of it, I saw him at the mini-mart yesterday evening.
&lrm;Nhớ lại thì tôi có thấy ông ấy tối qua &lrm;ở cửa hàng tiện lợi.
Around what time?
&lrm;Khoảng mấy giờ?
Well, it was when we were buying bento boxes for dinner.
&lrm;À, lúc đó chúng tôi đang mua &lrm;cơm hộp cho bữa tối.
I remember being worried about their expiration date
&lrm;Tôi nhớ là còn lo lắng &lrm;về hạn sử dụng của nó,
and asking Noriya what day it was.
&lrm;nên có hỏi Noriya hôm đó là ngày mấy.
You asked a child what the date was?
&lrm;Anh hỏi đứa bé về ngày à?
Yeah! I was holding the shopping basket.
&lrm;Vâng. Lúc ấy cháu đang cầm &lrm;giỏ của cửa hàng.
It had a newspaper in it that we were going to buy.
&lrm;Trong ấy có một tờ báo &lrm;mà bọn cháu sắp mua.
I told him that "August 13th" was written on it.
&lrm;Cháu bảo anh ấy &lrm;trên báo ghi ngày 13 tháng Tám.
I said that was the day that the Kamen Yaiba movie was gonna be on TV.
&lrm;Cháu nói đó là ngày &lrm;phim &lrm;Kamen Yaiba&lrm; chiếu trên ti-vi.
If it was the 13th, that means it was yesterday.
&lrm;Nếu thế thì là hôm qua.
When you saw him, was Mr. Yasutomi with anyone?
&lrm;Anh thấy ông ta đi với ai lúc ấy không?
No, I think he was by himself.
&lrm;Không, tôi nghĩ ông ấy đi một mình.
Say, Noriya... Did Toshinari get up to go to the bathroom or anything
&lrm;Này Noriya, anh Toshinari có vào nhà tắm &lrm;hay làm gì đấy
while you were watching the movie?
&lrm;khi cậu đang xem phim không?
No, I was sitting against him the whole time.
&lrm;Không, tớ ngồi với anh ấy suốt.
What did you do after it was over?
&lrm;Hết phim thì cậu làm gì?
It ended before 9:00, right?
&lrm;Phim hết trước chín giờ đúng không?
Yeah! I went to pee right after it ended and then I went back to playing my game.
&lrm;Ừ, sau đó tớ đi tè
"Went back to"? You were playing it before the movie, too?
&lrm;"Quay lại" à? Cậu đã chơi &lrm;trước khi xem phim sao?
Yeah, I played from the time we got back from the store until the movie started.
&lrm;Ừ, tớ chơi từ lúc đi cửa hàng tiện lợi về &lrm;đến khi phim bắt đầu.
Toshinari looked at his watch and said,
&lrm;Anh Toshinari nhìn đồng hồ và nói:
"Oh, no! It's already 7:00!
&lrm;"Ôi, đã bảy giờ rồi,
The movie's starting, so we'd better save our game."
&lrm;phim sắp bắt đầu &lrm;nên em lưu trò chơi lại đi." &lrm;Bọn tớ vội vàng lưu lại rồi mở ti-vi lên.
We did it just in time, because the movie had just started!
&lrm;Vừa kịp lúc phim bắt đầu.
While you were in the bathroom after the movie ended,
&lrm;Trong lúc cậu vào nhà vệ sinh &lrm;sau khi phim kết thúc,
Toshinari didn't leave the apartment?
&lrm;anh Toshinari có ra khỏi nhà không?
Nope, he asked me what kind of snacks I wanted from outside the bathroom door.
&lrm;Không, anh ấy đứng ngoài cửa phòng tắm &lrm;và hỏi tớ muốn ăn loại bánh nào.
Then you played your game together all evening after that?
&lrm;Rồi hai người chơi game &lrm;cả buổi tối hôm ấy à?
That's right! We played until pretty late,
&lrm;Đúng thế. Bọn tớ chơi đến tận khuya,
and then after I got up early and played some more,
&lrm;rồi tớ lại dậy sớm chơi tiếp.
I went to the store with Toshinari to go buy breakfast.
&lrm;Sau đó, tớ đến cửa hàng với anh Toshinari &lrm;để mua bữa sáng,
After that, I played until around noon or so.
&lrm;rồi lại chơi đến giữa trưa.
Then I got tired, so I took a nap.
&lrm;Xong tớ mệt quá nên lăn ra ngủ.
After I woke up, I played some more,
&lrm;Sau khi dậy, tớ chơi tiếp
and then I got hungry, so we went to the store.
&lrm;đến khi đói bụng, rồi lại ra cửa hàng.
And that's when I ran into you guys! Talk about gaming night and day!
&lrm;Và tình cờ gặp các cậu ở đấy.
That's why your rank was so high!
&lrm;Thảo nào lên được cấp cao thế.
I'm jealous!
&lrm;Ghen tị thật đấy!
What about lunch, then?
&lrm;Còn bữa trưa thì sao?
Oh, I'd been snacking all day, so I wasn't hungry at all.
&lrm;À, tớ ăn vặt cả ngày nên không đói.
Snacking and gaming all day!
&lrm;Ăn vặt và chơi game cả ngày.
-That's so great! -I'd call that Heaven!
&lrm;- Thích quá! &lrm;- Đúng là thiên đường!
Don't follow his example.
&lrm;Đừng bắt chước cậu ấy!
So you were with Toshinari all day again today?
&lrm;Xem ra cả ngày hôm nay &lrm;cậu đều ở với anh Toshinari nhỉ?
After we ate breakfast, he said he had an errand to run,
&lrm;Sau khi ăn sáng, anh ấy bảo &lrm;có công chuyện phải ra ngoài,
so I should play my game while he was out.
&lrm;nên tớ lại chơi game khi anh ấy vắng nhà.
He didn't want the man next door to get mad at us again,
&lrm;Anh ấy không muốn &lrm;bác hàng xóm lại nổi giận,
so he said to play with headphones on.
&lrm;nên bảo tớ đeo tai nghe vào rồi chơi.
When was that?
&lrm;- Lúc ấy mấy giờ? &lrm;- Để nhớ xem...
It was around 6 o'clock when we went to the store to buy breakfast,
&lrm;Lúc bọn tớ đi mua bữa sáng &lrm;là khoảng sáu giờ
and that was right after we came home and ate it,
&lrm;và bọn tớ về nhà ăn ngay sau đó,
so I guess that was around 7:00.
&lrm;nên tớ đoán là khoảng bảy giờ.
The clock behind the cashier at the store said it was just after 6:00.
&lrm;Đồng hồ phía sau cô thu ngân &lrm;chỉ qua sáu giờ.
What? Do you suspect the brother?
&lrm;Sao thế? Cậu nghi ngờ anh ta à?
Excuse me...
&lrm;À, xin lỗi...
Would you mind if we went back to my apartment?
&lrm;Liệu tôi có thể trở về phòng mình &lrm;được không?
I'd rather not make these kids hang around a dead body.
&lrm;Không thể để bọn trẻ loanh quanh &lrm;cạnh xác chết được.
Good point.
&lrm;Ừ nhỉ.
Just to rule you out, I'd like to go through your garbage and things.
&lrm;Tạm thời,
-Is that all right? -Sure, that's fine.
&lrm;- Được chứ? &lrm;- Vâng, tất nhiên rồi.
Hey, I know you!
&lrm;Này, tôi nhận ra anh rồi.
You weren't at the florist's earlier, were you?
&lrm;Vừa rồi anh có đến cửa hàng hoa &lrm;phải không?
Yes, I bought some flowers.
&lrm;Vâng, tôi có mua ít hoa.
I thought so!
&lrm;Tôi biết mà.
When I asked what kind of flowers to give someone when a wish comes true,
&lrm;Khi tôi hỏi ông chủ cửa hàng &lrm;nên tặng loại hoa nào
the guy there said, "How about a bouquet of false dragonheads
&lrm;Ông ấy nói: "Một bó hoa giả long đầu
like that man just bought?"
&lrm;như người kia vừa mua thì sao?"
I caught a glimpse of you just as you were leaving.
&lrm;Tôi có thoáng thấy anh khi anh vừa rời đi.
So you just got some good news, Detective Takagi?
&lrm;Thế chú vừa có tin vui à, chú Takagi?
Did you win a prize on your ice cream stick?
&lrm;Chú vừa thắng giải một cây kem à?
C'mon, tell us!
&lrm;Kể bọn cháu nghe đi!
Uh, well... Help me out here!
&lrm;Hả? Này, giúp anh với!
Huh? Why?
&lrm;Cái gì? Tại sao?
I said I'd do right by you, didn't I?
&lrm;Việc anh nói sẽ làm cho em đấy, nhớ không?
Oh, that.
&lrm;À, cái đấy.
Well, you're partly to blame for my little situation.
&lrm;Trong chuyện đấy &lrm;anh cũng có một phần lỗi mà,
I'd say it's only natural that you man up and do the right thing.
&lrm;nên anh phải ra mặt để sửa sai chứ.
Y-You have a point.
&lrm;Em nói cũng đúng.
That's the flower you bought?
&lrm;- Đấy là hoa anh mua à? &lrm;- Ừ.
In that case,
&lrm;Thế nghĩa là
did you also have some kind of wish come true?
&lrm;anh vừa có điều ước thành sự thật sao?
Y-Yes... I suppose.
&lrm;À, ừ.
Mr. Shiga. Shall we go to your apartment, then?
&lrm;Anh Shiga, chúng ta &lrm;qua căn hộ của anh nhé.
S-Sure...
&lrm;À vâng...
Say, Detective Takagi.
&lrm;Này, chú Takagi.
What is it, Conan?
&lrm;Gì thế Conan?
There's something I'd like you to find out for me.
&lrm;Có chuyện này cháu muốn nhờ &lrm;chú tìm hiểu giúp.
Toshinari placed those flowers by the road in front of that florist's,
&lrm;Toshinari đã đặt bó hoa ấy &lrm;trên con đường ngay trước tiệm hoa,
so I was wondering if there had been an accident there.
&lrm;nên cháu thắc mắc là có tai nạn nào &lrm;xảy ra ở đấy hay không.
- Oh, he did? - Come on. Quit dawdling, Takagi.
&lrm;- Anh ta đã làm thế à? &lrm;- Nhanh lên. Đừng lề mề nữa Takagi.
S-Sure...
&lrm;- Vâng. &lrm;- Nhanh lên!
He's probably the one who murdered Mr. Yasutomi.
&lrm;Anh ta chính là &lrm;người đã giết ông Yasutomi.
It was Toshinari Shiga, I'm sure of it.
&lrm;Chính là Toshinari Shiga, mình chắc chắn.
And the murder weapon is probably in...
&lrm;Và hung khí có thể là...
But the problem is his alibi.
&lrm;Nhưng vấn đề là &lrm;chứng cứ ngoại phạm của anh ta.
At the time of the murder, 7:00 to 9:00 on the evening of August 13th,
&lrm;Vào thời gian xảy ra vụ giết người, &lrm;từ bảy đến chín giờ,
he was right next to Noriya the whole time.
&lrm;anh ta ở bên cạnh Noriya suốt.
Damn it...
&lrm;Khỉ thật!
How the hell did you murder Mr. Yasutomi?
&lrm;Rốt cuộc thì làm sao &lrm;anh ta giết được ông Yasutomi?
Well?
&lrm;Sao?
Takagi? Did you get some good news today, then?
&lrm;Takagi, anh có tin gì vui hôm nay à?